Guide to the Yevgeny Yevtushenko Papers M1088
Department of Special Collections and University Archives
- Manuscripts, Series 3.
  - Subseries 3. Prose
    - "Pontifikatori", 2000 Sep. 11 (Box 89, Folder 14)
      Signed typescript, 5p., 2000 Sep. 11.
    - "A Precocious Autobiography", undated (Box 89, Folder 15)
      Signed handwritten fragments, 2p., n. d.; fragment of typescript, 3p., n. d.
    - "Prisoner of the mountains", undated (Box 89, Folder 16)
      Introduction to film, fragment, typescript, 2p., n. d.
    - "Rainbow in Manhattan", undated (Box 89, Folder 17)
      Signed typescript, 1p., n. d.
    - "Rasputin's Ring", undated (Box 89, Folder 18)
      Signed typescript 1p., n. d.
    - "Smertnyi prigovor post-modernizmu", 2001 Feb. 20 (Box 89, Folder 19)
      Signed typescript 2p., 2001 Feb. 20.
    - Speech [about Pushkin], undated (Box 89, Folder 20)
      Signed handwritten draft, 1p., n. d.
    - Speech: Memorial service for Kulish, Savva, undated (Box 89, Folder 21)
      Signed typescript, 2p., n. d.
    - Speech [about Uzbekistan], Jul. 11 (Box 89, Folder 22)
      Signed typescript, 2p., (?) Jul. 11.
    - "Sto dnei odnogo veka: 1953. Pokhoroni Stalina", undated (Box 89, Folder 23)
      Signed faxcpy, 4p., n. d.
    - "Taxi Jaws", "Bitrayed Victory", undated (Box 89, Folder 24)
      Typescript 3p., n. d.
    - Drafts, undated (Box 89, Folder 25)
      Drafs: untitled, n. d.
    - Drafts, undated (Box 89, Folder 26)
      Drafs: untitled (in English), n. d.
    - Drafts, undated (Box 89, Folder 27)
      Drafs: miscellaneous, fragments, n. d.
    - Posters: Bratsakaia GES, Detskii Sad, Pokhorony Stalina, undated (Box Na4, Folder 2)
      "Bratskaia GES" includes two posters with signatures, likely of the cast [?]; "Detskii Sad" - includes a very large poster in French; "Pokhorony Stalina" - includes a color poster in English.
    - A Poet Against the Destroyers, undated; Accession 2004-022; Copy of publication (Box 97, Folder 1)
    - City of the Yellow Devil [Unfinished], 2003; Accession 2004-022; Signed typescript (Box 97, Folder 2)
    - City of the Yellow Devil [Unfinished], 2003; Accession 2004-022; Signed typescript (Box 97, Folder 2)
    - Eulogies, 1994 - 2002; Accession 2004-022; Copy and faxcoy of publications (Box 97, Folder 3)
    - Farewell to the Twentieth Century [Preface to the Book "Wolf Passport"], 1997; Accession 2004-022; Typescript signed by Yevtushenko; includes letter to Europa Verlag from Albert Todd. (Box 97, Folder 4)
    - Film-making, It Is a Journy [Interview with Fellini], 2003 May; Accession 2004-022; Signed typescript (Box 97, Folder 5)
    - God Is Made Man [Essay about Pasternak], 1996; Accession 2004-022; Faxcopy of pulbication (Box 97, Folder 6)
    - If All Danes Were Jews, 1996 Jan.; Accession 2004-022; Bound and signed copy (Box 97, Folder 7)
    - Interview with "Encore", 1972 March 11; Accession 2004-022; Copies of typescript; includes letter to Albert Todd. (Box 97, Folder 8)
    - Introduction to Platonov's "The Pit", 1968; Accession 2004-022; Copy of typescript; copy of typescript of translation; letters to Albert Todd, 1968 - 1971. (Box 97, Folder 9)
    - Introduction to a Book [?], undated; Accession 2004-022; Signed and annotated fragments (Box 97, Folder 10)
      In English and Russian.
    - On Yevtushenko's Autobiography, 1963; Accession 2004-022; Copy of clipping (Box 97, Folder 11)
      In Russian
    - Speech [at a concert?], 2002 Dec. 14; Accession 2004-022; Annotated and signed typescript (Box 97, Folder 12)
    - Speech "A Lonely Hair from the Cheshir Cat's Tail", 1996; Accession 2004-022; Signed typescript (Box 97, Folder 13)
    - Speech "Poetry - the Mother of Human Subtlety", 1995; Accession 2004-022; Signed typescript (Box 97, Folder 14)
    - Speech "Russia's Amateur Justice", 1995 Oct. 23; Accession 2004-022; Printed in "Stetson Law Review" 1996 Nov. 4 (Box 97, Folder 15)
    - The Chicken-God, 1965 Aug.; Accession 2004-022; Clipping from "Harper's Magazine" (Box 97, Folder 16)
    - The Key to the Russian Soul, 1993; Accession 2004-022; Table of contents (Box 97, Folder 17)
    - Thousand Miles from One Hearth to Another, undated; Accession 2004-022; Clipping from magazine (Box 97, Folder 18)
    - We Try Harder [Pearl Harbor] [1 of 2], 1966 -67; Accession 2004-022; Photocopy of typescript; includes publication in "Yunost'" [russian magazine] (Box 97, Folder 19)
      in Russian
    - We Try Harder [Pearl Harbor] [2 of 2], 1968; Accession 2004-022; Translation by Albert Todd; includes copy of a letter from Albert Todd to Laurence, Michael. (Box 97, Folder 20)
    - Warnography, undated; Accession 2004-022; Handwritten draft, signed; handwritten draft and annotated typescript of translation by Albert Todd. (Box 97, Folder 21)
- Manuscripts by Others, Series 4.
  In addition to poems and essays sent to Yevtushenko by his friends and admirers, famous and unknown, this series includes poetry by Yevtushenko's father, A. R. Gangnus, and correspondence lessons in Geometry by his grandfather.
  - Adamov, V.: "Materializm i bessmertie", undated (Box 30, Folder 9)
    Adamov, V.
  - Ajzenstadt, Michael: Excerpted from "Poetic Justice", 1997 (Box 30, Folder 10)
    Faxcopy typescript, 2 p., 1997 Nov. 10
    Ajzenstadt, Michael
  - Akhmadulina, Bella: "V promezhutke mezh zvukom i slovom", undated (Box 30, Folder 11)
    Copy of typescript, 7 p., n.d.
  - Anninskii, L.: "Moda priznanie," [about Yevtushenko], 1959 Dec. (Box 30, Folder 12)
    Annotated copy of typescript, 9 p., 1959 Dec.
    Anninskii, L.
  - Antolotsi, Zoltan: "Rakety i telegi,", 1981 Oct. 30 (Box 30, Folder 13)
    Fragment of typescript, printed in "Mad'iar Nemzet", 2 p., 1981 Oct. 30.
    Antolotsi, Zoltan
  - Arizala, José: "Evtushenko en Colombia", undated (Box 30, Folder 14)
    By José Rizala, APN correspondent; typescript, 5 p., n.d.
    Arizala, José
  - Beach, Geraldine: review [of "Don't Die Before You're Dead"?], undated (Box 30, Folder 15)
    Beach, Geraldine
  - Bien, Jeff, undated (Box 30, Folder 16)
    Biography, 1 p. Includes the following poems: "As the walls came down," "America," "Marrakesh," "Staten Island."
    Bien, Jeff
  - Birmann, Vol'f: "Pesni", 1994 Sept. 19 (Box 31, Folder 1)
    Translated by E. Maasa and S. Pozdniakova. Booklet bound with ribbon, 15 p., 1994 Sept. 19.
    Maasa, E.; Pozdniakova, S.; Birmann, Vol'f
  - Brodsky, I.: "Na smert' druga", undated (Box 31, Folder 2)
    Brodsky, I.
  - Bubar, Erika: "Poems", 1985 (Box 31, Folder 3)
    Handwritten letter to Yevtushenko from Myra on New York State Poets in the Schools/Poets in Public Service letterhead, 1 p., 1985 July 1. Stapled booklet of poems, with a photograph of the author, 1985.
    Bubar, Erika
  - Charkviani, D.: "Tiazhest' neulovimosti", 1983 (Box 31, Folder 4)
    Printed in "Zolotye vspleski", 1983. Two copies of typescripts, 2 p. ea., 1983.
    Charkviani, D.
  - Clemens, Walter C.: "The McDonaldization of Russian Culture?", undated (Box 31, Folder 5)
    Typescript, 4 p., n.d.
    Clemens, Walter C.
  - Dalton, Catherine Isabel: "Yevgeny Yevtushenko's 'The Thirteen': A Translation and Discussion", 1998 May (Box 31, Folder 6)
    Faxcopy of letter from Catherine Dalton to Yevtushenko requesting information, 1 p., 1998 Apr. 20; hardbound copy of thesis, 1998 May.
    Dalton, Catherine
  - Demidov, Anatolii: "Poet vsekh khoroshikh liudei", 1978 Dec. 5 - 20 (Box 31, Folder 7)
    Copy of typescript, 30 p., 1978 Dec. 5 - 20.
    Demidov, Anatolii
  - Duncan, Mary: Interview "Yevgeny Yevtushenko", 1993 June - July (Box 31, Folder 8)
    Typescript, 19 p., 1993.
    Duncan, Mary
  - Dutton, Geoffrey: "A Russian Journey" [a collection of poems], undated (Box 31, Folder 9)
    Signed copies of typescripts, 21 p., n.d.
  - Feldek, Liubomir (Lubomir), 1987 - 1988 (Box 31, Folder 10)
    "Gorbacov Pise Astrid Lindgrenovej," photocopy from journal, 1 p., 1987 [?]. "Pis'mo Yevgeniiu Yevtushenko," typescript, 7 p., n.d. "Pis'mo Yevgeniiu Yevtushenko," copy of typescript, 8 p., 1988 June.
    Feldek, Lubomir
  - Franklin, B. Keith: "Muses by BeKiF", 1997 (Box 31, Folder 11)
    Spiral bound book of poems with a handwritten inscription to Yevtushenko.
    Franklin, B. Keith
  - Gabor, Horvath: [Interview for NEPSZABADSAG?], 1996 Mar. (Box 31, Folder 12)
    Interview of Yevtushenko by Gabor, typescript, 3 p., 1996 Mar.
    Gabor, Horvath
  - Gangnus, A.R.[Yevtushenko's father], 1924 - 1926 (Box 31, Folder 13)
    Handwritten table of contents, copy of typescript of poems, ca. 101 p., 1924 - 1926.
    Gangnus, A.R.
  - Gangnus, A.R. [Yevtushenko's father], 1926 - 1941 (Box 31, Folder 14)
    Typescripts of poems, 1926 - 1941.
  - Gangnus, A.R. [Yevtushenko's father], 1925 - 1941 (Box 31, Folder 15)
    Handwritten table of contents, 1 p., n.d. Copy of typescript, 58 p., 1925 - 1941.
  - Gangnus, R. V. (Yevtushenko's grandfather): "Zaochnaia shkola 2-i stupendi dlia vzroslykh: Geometria", 1931 (Box 31, Folder 16)
    Two stapled booklets published by "Gosudarstvennoe uchebno-pedagogicheskoe izdatelstvo" in Moscow. Lessons 15 and 17.
    Gangnus, R.V.
  - Ginsberg, Allen: "Capitol Air", 1980 Dec. 15 (Box 31, Folder 17)
    Photocopy from journal with annotations, 1 p., 1980 Dec. 15.
  - Gippius, Z: "Svecha Nenavisti", 1921 (Box 31, Folder 18)
    Copy of typescript, 1 p., 1921.
    Gippius, Z.
  - Gracheva, N., 1986 - 1988 (Box 31, Folder 19)
    Poems. Copies of typescripts, 1986 - 1988.
    Gracheva, Nina
  - Grinberg, Regina: "Odna iz mord svobody - Eto svoboda oskorblenii", undated (Box 31, Folder 20)
    Grinberg, Regina
  - Grue, Lee Meitzen: "For Yevgeny Yevtushenko on the occasion of his visit to New Orleans", 1985 July 4 (Box 31, Folder 21)
    Collection of poems, typescript, 6 p., 1985.
    Grue, Lee Meitzen
  - Gumilev, N., undated (Box 31, Folder 22)
    Poem, typescript, 1 p., n.d.
    Gumilev, N.
  - Harris, Jeane H.: "Yevgeny Yevtushenko: Stolichnaya in a Red Suit", 1995 (Box 31, Folder 23)
    Typescript, 2 p., ca. 1995.
    Harris, Jeane H.
  - Hoagland, Guy: "Friend" and "White Spring", 1992 Dec. 30 (Box 31, Folder 24)
    Typescript, 2 p., 1992 Dec. 30.
    Hoagland, Guy
  - Ialan-Shtekelis, Miriam: "Pis'mo Russkomu Poetu", 1962 (Box 31, Folder 25)
    Photocopy of poem from book entitled Vetvi: Stikhi i proza.
    Ialan-Shtekelis, Miriam
  - Ioffe, Solomon X.: "Tri chitatelia na odnogo pisatelia: Odin Yevtushenko, dve Galiny Vishnevskikh, ili chto takoe literatura", undated (Box 31, Folder 26)
    Ioffe, Solomon
  - Izbitser, Alexander: Translation of Isaak Glikman's "Letters to a Friend", 1995 - 1998 (Box 31, Folder 27)
    Includes a handwritten letter to Yevutshenko from Izbitser, 3 p., ca. 1998 Oct. 11; letter to Kurt Masur from Izbitser concerning the manuscript; portions of Glikman's "Letters to a Friend" concerning his correspondence with Shostakovich in English, typescript; flyer for Izbitser performance.
    Glikman, Isaak; Izbitser, Alexander; Masur, Kurt; Shostakovich, Dmitriéi Dmitrie
  - Johns, Melissa G.: "Works", 1993 (Box 31, Folder 28)
    Collection of poems, typescript, 7 p., 1993.
    Johns, Melissa G.
  - Kavyl, Michas: Between the Conflagrations, 1990 (Box 31, Folder 29)
    Copies from book, 4 p., 1990
    Kavyl, Michas
  - Kudimova, Marina, 1976 Sept. 19 - Oct. 2 (Box 31, Folder 30)
    Handwritten draft, typescripts, 1976 Sept. 19 - Oct. 2.
  - Leopardi, Giacomo: "Versi del Conte Giacomo Leopardi", undated (Box 31, Folder 31)
    Handwritten note, 1 p., n.d. "La Vita Solitaria: Idillio VI", photocopy, 1 p., n.d.
    Leopardi, Giacomo
  - Levinson, A.: "Cricket in the Mill and Other Poems", undated (Box 31, Folder 32)
    Typescript with handwritten signed note on first page, 18 p., n.d.
    Levinson, A.
  - Lisianskii, Mark: "Razroznennye stranitsy - etiudy iz moikh zapisnykh knizhek", undated (Box 31, Folder 33)
    Lisianskii, Mark
  - Lizen, A.: "A tigry rychali: Nezabyvaemaia vstrecha s Yevgeniem Yevtushenko", undated (Box 31, Folder 34)
    Signed copy of typescript, 10 p., n.d.
    Lizen, A.
  - Lotonenko, V.D. [?], 1997 Apr. (Box 32, Folder 1)
    Copies of typescripts, 1997 Apr.
    Lotonenko, V.D.
  - Maksimov, Vladimir, 1967 Nov. (Box 32, Folder 2)
    Note to Igor' Ivanovich from Irena Lesnevskaia, typescript, 1 p., n.d. Poem, typescript, 1 p., 1967 Nov.
    Maksimov, Vladimir
  - Matveeva, Novella: "Pravda istinnaia i sluzhenie ei", undated (Box 32, Folder 3)
    Typescript, 5 p., n.d.
    Matveeva, Novella
  - Mezhirov, Aleksandr, 1982 Aug. (Box 32, Folder 4)
    "Ty, Zhenia, znaesh'..."; typescript, 5 p., n.d. "Okopnyi Nefrit;" signed copy of typescript, 2 p., 1982 Aug.
    Mezhirov, Aleksandr
  - Mikhailov, Vladimir: "Fragmenty zhizni i sud'by, Interv'iu s Yevgeniem Yevtushenko", 1989 (Box 32, Folder 5)
    Copy of typescript, 17 p., ca. 1989.
    Mikhailov, Vladimir
  - Monakhinia, Mariia: "Rasizm i Religiia", undated (Box 32, Folder 6)
    Photocopy from book, 4 p., n.d.
    Monakhinia, Mariia
  - Morgunov, A.B., 1980 - 1982 (Box 32, Folder 7)
    Collection of poems; copy of typescript, 1980 - 1982.
    Morgunov, A.B.
  - Nekhoroshev, Iurii, 1989 Feb. 12 (Box 32, Folder 8)
    "Vtoroi chernovoi variant stat'i 'Kak staryi Fel'dfebel' s novobrantsami...' (novoe nazvanie)"; copy of typescript, 11 p., n.d. "Vykidysh," signed typescript, 5 p., 1989 Feb. 12.
  - Neruda, Pablo, undated (Box 32, Folder 9)
    Torn hardback, back-cover; "Yevtushenko rekhnulsia...", 1 p., n.d. Page from book, "Evtuchenko es un loco,...", 1 p., n.d.
  - Ogden, Charles: "Medal of Honor" or "Break of Day," One Act Play, 1967 Dec. 15 (Box 32, Folder 10)
    Letter from Ogden to Yevtushenko, signed typescript, 1 p., 1967 Dec. 15. Play, typescript, 16 p., n.d.
    Ogden, Charles
  - Paci, Francisco Paolo, 1981 (Box 32, Folder 11)
    Color pen and ink drawing with text, 1 p., 1981.
    Paci, Francisco Paolo
  - Pal'mova, Svetlana: "Sovetskii Sport - Moia Gazeta Mama: interv'iu po mezhdunarodnoi telefonnoi linii Moskva - N'iu Iork s poetom Yevgeniem Yevtushenko", 1999 (Box 32, Folder 12)
    Handwritten, signed note from Yevtushenko to "readers", 1 p., ca. 1999. Faxcopy of signed typescript, 5 p., ca. 1999.
    Pal'mova, Svetlana
  - Pazdnikov, Ivan Vasil'evichna, 1997 June 7 (Box 32, Folder 13)
    Stapled booklet with typed poems glued, 7 p., 1997 June 7
    Pazdnikov, Ivan
  - Petrov, David: "Nochnoi zvonok (Yevgenii Yevtushenko)", undated (Box 32, Folder 14)
    Copy of typescript, 26 p., n.d.
    Petrov, David
  - Popov, Igor: Draft of interview for "Argumenty i Facty", 1999 July 12 (Box 32, Folder 15)
    Annotated faxcopy of typescript, 12 p., 1999 July 12.
    Popov, Igor
  - Rasskazova, Tat'iana: "Yevgenii Yevtushenko: Menia zapuskali v fortochku, chtob ia otkryval dveri iz nutri": Variant dlia "Stolitsy", undated (Box 32, Folder 16)
    Typescript, 6 p.
    Rasskazova, Tat'iana
  - Ratner, David: "Yevgeny Yevtushenko", 1985 May 6 (Box 32, Folder 17)
    Paper for World Lit. Honors class. Typescript, 18 p., 1985 May 6.
    Ratner, David
  - Rein, Evgenii, 1982 Jan. 9 - 31 (Box 32, Folder 18)
    Poems, typescripts with handwritten notes, 3 p., 1982 Jan.
    Rein, Evgenii
  - Sánchez, Ricardo: "American Journeys::Jornadas Americanas", 1993 (Box 32, Folder 19)
    Collection of poems in Spanish and English. Photocopy of signed typescript, 40 p., 1993.
    Sánchez, Ricardo
  - Sánchez, Ricardo: "Canto a Eugenio", 1993 Dec. 28 (Box 32, Folder 20)
    Typescript, 3 p., 1993 Dec. 28.
  - Shtein, E.: "Volshebnye zvuki slova", 1995 (Box 32, Folder 21)
    Annotated typescript, 8 p., 1995.
    Shtein, E.
  - Slutskii, Boris, undated (Box 32, Folder 22)
    "Natsional'nye zhaloby", copy of typescript, 1 p. "Poluchil vsemirnyi mikrofon...", copy of typescript, 1 p.
    Slutskii, Boris
  - Smith, William Jay, 1970 (Box 32, Folder 23)
    Copy of typescript, 1 p., ca. 1970 Apr.
  - Sobchak, A.A.: "Problemy Rossiiskoi Konstitutsii", 1998 (Box 32, Folder 24)
    Inscribed copy.
    Sobchak, A.A.
  - Sokolov, Vl.: "Pravda, Pravda, i tol'ko Pravda", 1972 May 19 (Box 32, Folder 25)
    Signed typescript, 5 p.
    Sokolov, V.
  - Svoboda, M.: "Evgeniiu Aleksandrovichu Yevtushenko ob Aleksandre Rudol'fovicha Gangnus", 1980 May 31 (Box 32, Folder 26)
    Handwritten notebook, 16 p., 1980 May 31.
    Svoboda, M.
  - Tandori, Dezhe: "Moi liubimyi poet Yevtushenko", undated (Box 32, Folder 27)
    Tandori, Dezhe
  - Treskin, Eduard: "Kak stat' kinozvezdoi?", undated (Box 32, Folder 28)
    Copy of typescript, 36 p., n.d.
    Treskin, Eduard
  - Turbina, Nina, 1981 - 1983 (Box 32, Folder 29)
    Collection of poems. Typescript, 19 p., 1981 - 1983
    Turbina, Nika
  - Vasil'ev, Iurii [close friend of Yevtushenko], 1995 (Box 32, Folder 30)
    Collection of poems entitled "Mozaiki". Copy of typescript, 16 p., n.d. "Ty moe operen'em[?]", copy of handwritten draft, 1 p., n.d. Three poems, photocopy of "Kolomensie izvestiia", 1 p., 1995 Oct. 10
    Vasil'ev, Iurii
  - Veshkin, Fedor Aleksandrovich: "Fed'ka - Vrag Naroda!", undated (Box 32, Folder 31)
    With signed letter, typescript 16 p.
    Veshkin, Fedor Aleksandrovich
  - Watson, Maurice T.: Review of The Collected Poems 1952-1990, 1996 (Box 32, Folder 32)
    Accepted by Opus Literary Review for Spring/Summer '96, 4 p.
    Watson, Maurice
  - Collection of poems by Georgian poets, undated (Box 32, Folder 33)
    Gudiashvili, Zvezda; Chiladze, Otar; Nishnianidze, Shota; Machavariani, Mukhran; Abashidze, Grigol; Tabidze, Galaktion; Nizharadze, Enver; Berulava, Khuta; Abshilava, Amiran; Tarba, Ivan
  - "Vecher poezii v Dome Spaso": 24ogo Maia 1990: Moskva, 1990 May 24 (Box 32, Folder 34)
    Collection of poems in stapled booklet, 69 p., 1990 May 24
    Ashbery, John; Wilbur, Richard; Voznesenskīĭ, Andreĭ
  - Interview with "Trud", undated (Box 32, Folder 35)
    Typescript, 9 p.
  - Interview: "Variant dlia 'Stasa'", undated (Box 32, Folder 36)
    Annotated copy of typescript, 6 p., n.d.
  - "Perechityvaia Yevtushenko", undated (Box 32, Folder 37)
    Copy of typescript, n.d.
  - "The Praise and Criticism of the Soviet Communist Government in Yevgeny Yevtushenko's Poetry", 1999 (Box 32, Folder 38)
    Typescript (printout from web), 3 p., 1999.
  - Vypiski iz kritiki, 1953 - 1959 (Box 32, Folder 39)
    Handwritten notes, 16 p., n.d.
  - "Writer as Conscience of the World": Jerusalem, 1993 (Box 32, Folder 40)
    "Report of a Forum in Jerusalem April 20 and 21, 1993; Jerusalem International Book Fair, The Aspen Institute."
  - Print out of published references to Yevtushenko and his work, 1959 - 1994 (Box 32, Folder 41)
  - Poems by Authors Aa - Jz, undated (Box 33, Folder 1)
  - Poems by Authors Ka - Z, undated (Box 33, Folder 2)
  - Poems by unidentified authors, undated (Box 33, Folder 2.1)
  - Annotated copies of poems by Akhmatova, Blok, Pasternak, Lermontov (Box 33, Folder 2.2)
  - Agrest, A.E.: Tekhnicheskoe zadanie na sostavlenie slovarei poezii Yevgeniia Aleksandrovicha Yevtushenko na EVM ES - 1022, 1979 (Box 33, Folder 3)
    Bound typescript with illustrations. Letter to Yevtushenko from Aleksandr Agrest, handwritten, 1 p., 1979.
    Agrest, A. E.
  - Unidentified Prose, undated (Box 33, Folder 4)
    Includes a quotation of Abraham Lincoln, 1 p.; a statement by Ernst Neizvestnyi [?].
    Neizvestnyi, E.
  - Teksty pesen na slova Yevg. Yevtushenko, undated (Box 33, Folder 5)
    List of 39 songs to Yevtushenko poems, typescript, 1 p., n.d.
  - Music by Balabanova, L. - "U rudnika Chikikamata", undated (Box 33, Folder 6)
    Musical score, n.d.
    Balabanova, L.
  - Music by Balian, Vladilen - "Vivan Tania" and "Zhelanie", undated (Box 33, Folder 7)
    Musical scores, multiple copies, n.d.
    Balian, Vladilen
  - Music by Bermin [?], Boris - "Drobitskii Iar", 1989 - 1995 (Box 33, Folder 8)
    Musical score, 1989 - 1995.
    Bermin, Boris
  - Music by Chepelianskii, Leonid - "Ostanovis'!", undated (Box 33, Folder 9)
    Copy of musical score, n.d.
    Chepelianskii, Leonid
  - Music by Dem'ianiuka, N., 1981 Aug. 15 (Box 33, Folder 10)
    Copy of musical score, 1981 Aug. 15.
    Dem'ianiuka, N.
  - Music by Kheifei, Vladimir (Heifetz) - "Babii Iar", 1962 (Box 33, Folder 11)
    Concert program, 1962 Apr. 29. Handwritten, bound musical score, n.d.
    Heifetz, Vladimir
  - Music by Holliday, Thomas - "Reflections Amid the Ice," "Autumn," "Colours," "What Pain, My Beloved," "Perfection", 1972 Feb. 15 (Box 33, Folder 12)
    Handwritten letter, 1 p., 1972 Feb. 15. Handwritten and copies of musical scores.
    Holliday, Thomas
  - Music by Illiutovich, Nina - "Nashi piatnadtsat' respublik!", 1969 Apr. 27 (Box 33, Folder 13)
    Handwritten musical score, 1969.
    Illiutovich, Nina
  - Music by Kazenina, V. - "Prikliucheniia Chipollino: Pesni iz kinofilma", 1979 (Box 33, Folder 14)
    Kazenina, V.
  - Music by Kochetova, M. - "Vozmezdie", 1979 - 1981 (Box 33, Folder 15)
    Handwritten letter to Yevtushenko from Kochetova, 1981 Apr. 16. Musical score bound with staples, 11 p., 1979 Apr. 26.
    Kochetova, M.
  - Music by Krylatov, Yevgeny - "Ballada o voennykh letchitsakh" iz k/f "V nebe nochnye ved'my", 1979 - 1981 (Box 33, Folder 16)
    Krylatov, Yevgeny
  - Music by Liapin, A. - "Ty ne zovi menia upriamoi", 1982 (Box 33, Folder 17)
    Letter to Yevtushenko from Liapin, handwritten, 1 p., 1982 Dec. 22. Musical score, 1982.
    Liapin, A.
  - Music by L'vova-Kompaneitsa, D. - "Bol'shaia ty, Rossiia", 1988 (Box 33, Folder 18)
    Musical score, 1 p., ca. 1988 [?].
    L'vova-Kompaneitsa, D.
  - Music by Osbon, David - "Gratitude", 1990 Aug. 23 (Box 33, Folder 19)
    Copy of musical score, 11 p., 1990 Aug. 23.
    Osbon, David
  - Music by Paikin, Girt - "Nezhnost'", 1988 (Box 33, Folder 20)
    Copies of musical scores in Russian and Hebrew, 1988 Dec. 8
    Paikin, Girt
  - Music by Pechnikov, Leonid - "Tvoe litso", 1985 Sept. 9 (Box 33, Folder 21)
    Typed and handwritten letter with poem to Yevtushenko from Pechnikov, 2 p., 1985 Sept. 9. Musical score, n.d.
    Pechnikov, Leonid
  - Music by Petrov, Andrei - "Pesni" including "nas v nabitykh tramvaiakh boltaet" and "Stekliannyi gospodin", 1991 (Box 33, Folder 22)
    Book of music by many writers (including Bella Akhmadulina and Yevtushenko), published 1991, ca. 78 p.
    Petrov, Andrei
  - Music by Pirkovskii, N. - "Vokal'nyi Tsikl", 1981 June 12 (Box 33, Folder 23)
    Book of Yevtushenko poems set to music, handwritten inscription to Yevtushenko, 43 p., 1981 June 12.
    Pirkovskii, N.
  - Music by Popova, A. - "Dolog Dozhd'", 1976 (Box 33, Folder 24)
    Handwritten musical score, 1976.
    Popova, A.
  - Music by Sazanakov, Viacheslav, 1989 Mar. (Box 33, Folder 25)
    Handwritten musical score, 1989 Mar.
    Sazanakov, Viacheslav
  - Music by Shakirova, R. - "Ostanovis', podumai!" and "romans o smysle zhizni", 1989 Mar. (Box 33, Folder 26)
    Shakirova, R.
  - Music by Shostakovich, R. - Symphony No. 13 - Babii Iar, undated (Box 33, Folder 27)
    Copies of the arrangement of words.
    Shostakovich, R.
  - Music by Silverman, Jerry - "Nochnoi bliuz", 1962 (Box 33, Folder 28)
    Magazine "Smena", 1962.
    Silverman, Jerry
  - Music by Suchkov, S. - "Povara svistiat", 1977 Jan. 3 (Box 33, Folder 29)
    Handwritten letter to Yevtushenko from Suchkov, 1 p., 1977 Jan. 3. Musical score, n.d.
    Suchkov, S.
  - Music by Udovitskii, V. - "Pamiati A.D. Sakharova", 1989 - 1990 (Box 33, Folder 30)
    Handwritten letter to Yevtushenko from Udovitskii, 1 p., n.d. Copy of musical score, bound with tape, 56 p., 1989 - 1990.
    Udovitskii, V.
  - Miscellaneous Musical Scores, undated (Box 33, Folder 31)
    "Protsukhal [?] progulka s synom." "Idut belye snegi"
  - Evans, Bev: "Words'" dedicated to Yevtushenko, 2000 Dec. (Box 90, Folder 1)
    Typescript, 5p., 2000 Dec.
    Evans, Bev
  - Gritsman, Andrei: "Kakoe vremia - takov Messia", 1997 (Box 90, Folder 2)